Inventory of the Governor and the Students Videotape Series, 1973-1974
Hoover Institution Archives
- Videorecordings, 1973-1974
  - Two-inch videoreels, 1973-1974 (Tape 27-76)
    - The Governor and the Students: Stockton Unified School District, 26 February 1974 (Tape 45 (1))
      Juniors and seniors at Edison, Stag, and Franklin high schools in the Stockton Unified School District asked about such polictical issues as the tuition increase at state colleges, gas rationing, the drinking age, women in politics, the Patty Hearst kidnapping, the state lottery, mental hospitals, the Peripheral Canal, and the desegregation lawsuit filed against a Stockton school. Before the program, a public service announcement on bicycle safety from the Office of Traffic Safety, State of California, features baseball player Frank Edwin "Tug" McGraw Jr. riding a ten-speed bike.
    - The Governor and the Students: Pleasant Hill High School (part 1), 13 March 1974 (Tape 46 (8))
      Seniors at Pleasant Hill High School ask Governor Reagan questions about political issues in California in 1974. Before the program, a public service announcement on motorcycle safety from the Office of Traffic Safety, State of California, features Los Angeles Rams quarterback John Hadl holding a motorcycle helmet and urging students to wear a helmet all the time when they ride.
      Sequence: PART 1 (22A): Slate (00:45), John Hadl motorcycle safety public service announcement (00:54), opening title sequence (01:18), Reagan introduces the program (01:39), first question (02:00), closing credit sequence (28:17).
      Each videotape represents a different program taped at the same location on the same day, identified on the slate as programs 22A and 22B.
    - The Governor and the Students: Pleasant Hill High School (part 2), 13 March 1974 (Tape 47 (15))
      Sequence: PART 2 (22B): Slate (01:29), John Hadl motorcycle safety public service announcement (01:46), opening title sequence (02:12), Reagan introduces the program (02:30), first question (02:46), closing credit sequence (29:08).
      To view the program, use the link for Pleasant Hill (program 1).
    - Rio Vista, time: 27:10, 18 March 1974 (Tape 48 (38))
    - Rio Vista, time: 26:45, 18 March 1974 (Tape 49 (23A and 23B))
    - Hi Band Color, time: 28:15, 19 April 1974 (Tape 50 (2))
    - Hi Band Color, time: 28:12, 19 April 1974 (Tape 51 (5))
    - Holmes-Land #22, 22 April 1974 (Tape 52 (22))
    - Car theft panel discussion (part 1), 13 May 1974 (Tape 53 (1A))
      Four men convicted of car theft in California are interviewed about their experiences stealing cars--how and why they did it, how they got caught, what prison is like, being on parole, as well as characteristics of various makes and models of cars. Their names are not known; it appears that they are introduced in the first few minutes of the program, during which there is no sound. This tape is part of the Governor and the Students video collection, but does not fit with that television series.
      Sequence data: First image/no sound (01:19), sound starts (02:22).
    - Car theft panel discussion (part 2), 13 May 1974 (Tape 54 (2A))
      Sequence data: First image (01:17), ends in mid-sentence (33:09)
    - The Governor and the Students: Loretto High School, 14 May 1974 (Tape 55 (6))
      This program features freshman, sophomore, junior, and senior students at Loretto High School, a girls school in Sacramento. It was filmed on location at Loretto High.
      Sequence: introductory slate (01:15), voice-over introduction (01:49), Reagan begins speaking (02:07), first question, about the lack of planning for the energy crisis despite warnings (02:53), voice-over closing (29:38), black (30:00).
    - It's No Life For Nobody, Master, time: 30:00, 22 July 1974 (Tape 56)
    - Holmes-Land, #39, Petaluma, Show #1A, time: 26:43, 4 September 1974 (Tape 57 (39))
    - The Governor and the Students: Petaluma, 4 September 1974 (Tape 58 (40))
      Students from three high schools ask Governor Ronald Reagan questions in press conference format. The students include (1) Petaluma High School student council members, (2) seniors from Casa Grande High School, and (3) ten top students and the student president of Rancho Cotate High School.
      Sequence: Slate (00:44), opening sequence (01:47), Reagan introduces program (02:09), first question, about the construction of Melones Dam on the Stanislaus River (02:45), closing credits (29:12).
      The opening sequence introduces this program as "Face the Students," described as "an unrehearsed, unedited dialog between California high school students and government leaders." Its format is otherwise identical to "The Governor and the Students." Additional Title: Face the Students: Petaluma.
    - Show #2B, time: 27:40, 18 September 1974 (Tape 59 (33))
    - Face the Students, Castro Valley High School, #2A (3), time: 27:50, 18 September 1974 (Tape 60 (34))
      Conditions Governing Access note
      Use copy reference number: 84078_v_0001525
    - Face the Students, Show #3B-Modoc and Orland, Master, time: 27:30, 9 October 1974 (Tape 61)
    - Face the Students, Show #4A, time: 28:00, 11 November 1974 (Tape 62)
    - Face the Students, Show #4B, time: 1 hour (28:03), 11 November 1974 (Tape 63)
    - Face the Students, Show #6A, Galt, time: 27:10, 13 November 1974 (Tape 64 (35))
    - Face the Students, Show #6B, time: 27:30, 13 November 1974 (Tape 65)
    - Face the Students, Show #13: Cozens, time: 28:30, 10 January 1975 (Tape 66)
    - Face the Students, Show #17, time: 28:30, 14 February 1975 (Tape 67)
    - Face the Students, 11 April 1975 (Tape 68)
    - The Governor and the Students: Luther Burbank High School (part 1), 24 May 1973 (Tape 69 (16))
      Juniors and seniors from a variety of subject-matter classes at Luther Burbank High School ask Governor Ronald Reagan questions.
      Sequence: Part 1: Opening slate (00:46), opening sequence (01:06), Reagan begins introduction (01:19), first question, about bombing in Cambodia (01:50), abrupt cut off in mid-sentence and closing credits (29:28).
      For part 2, see tape 73. This program appears to be the same as the program on tape 8.
    - Holmes-Land, time: 21:50, undated (Tape 70 (18))
    - Holmes-Land, interviews, time: 30:00, undated (Tape 71 (19))
    - Holmes-Land, #23, time: 25:15, undated (Tape 72 (23))
    - The Governor and the Students: Luther Burbank High School (part 2), 22 May 1973 (Tape 73 (30))
      Part 2: Opening slate (00:30), opening sequence (00:45), Reagan begins speaking (01:00), first question, about guaranteed annual income (01:13).
      For part 1, see tape 69. This program appears to be the same as the program on tape 8.
    - Untitled, undated (Tape 74)
    - Governor Ronald Reagan bill signing, time: 09:17, undated (Tape 75)
      Footage of Reagan signing a bill concerning occupational health and safety. He says it will retain OSHA protections in state hands; it is a real getting together of labor and management.
      Sequence data: Reagan speaks (00:35), Reagan signs (01:00), Reagan presents souvenir pens and bills (01:54), Reagan gets up from desk, formal session ends, views of people mixing (04:03), Reagan seated at desk for special photographs (05:37), Reagan makes "compulsive doodler" comment (05:46), Reagan remembers his time with Screen Actors Guild negotiating with producers in Rexall building (06:45), Reagan posed at desk (07:10), Reagan stands to leave and shakes hands (07:45).
    - Untitled, undated (Tape 76)
  - U-matic videocassette, undated (Tape 77)
    - San Diego, time: 28:30, undated (Tape 77)